Already have LifeCare services? [Sign In](https://lcc30.lifecare.com/index.html) or [Register](https://lcc30.lifecare.com/registration/register1.rtml?e=&textonly=&target_url=&banner=)

[

](https://www.lifecare.com/)

Menu

* Products

LifeCare® Privacy Policy
========================

LifeCare’s Privacy Policy (the “Privacy Policy”) will advise you about how we collect, use, share and protect your personal information.

Unless we say otherwise, this Privacy Policy applies to your use of all of the sites and services owned or operated by LifeCare, Inc. (“LifeCare”), including any site that we may own or operate in the future (collectively, the “LifeCare Sites”). This policy does not apply to any sites other than the LifeCare Sites. As used in this policy, terms such as “we” or “our” and “Company” refers to LifeCare.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. We may need to change this Privacy Policy from time to time, so you should refer back to this Privacy Policy regularly. Your use of the LifeCare Sites after changes have been made shall be deemed to be your acceptance of any changes. If you do not accept any changes that are made to this Privacy Policy, do not use the LifeCare Sites.

THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT
--------------------------

We may collect two basic types of information: [Personal Information](https://wl.lifecare.com/group/guest/privacy-policy#ScreenTips) ( as defined in this policy) and [Anonymous Information](https://wl.lifecare.com/group/guest/privacy-policy#ScreenTips "Anonymous information means information that does not directly or indirectly identify, and cannot reasonably be used to identify, an individual guest.") (as defined in this policy).

**Personal Information** – In connection with services, you or your employer or sponsoring organization (“Sponsor Organization”) must provide certain information so we can identify you and provide you services as you requested. Examples of such data include:

* Registration Information – Information such as your first name, last name and email address and in some cases, Member ID or Company Registration code are collected during registration. In some cases, this information is provided to LifeCare directly by you or your Sponsor Organization.LifeCare also collects a secret question which you will use for online password resets or identifying you when calling in for assistance. Once logged in, you may decide to provide other optional data types such as home address(s), phone #(s) to assist with transactions (described below). In some cases, you have the ability to extend your benefits to family members at which point we collect information such as the family member’s first name, last name, gender and the relationship to you.
* Transactional Information – In order to fulfill your request for services (i.e. information, referrals, services and/or discounts in a region you specify) we may need to collect additional information such as residence address and supporting details surrounding your particular need for the service. This maybe acquired Chat, Email, or a call depending on your Sponsor Organization’s plan, we may be required to collect credit card information to fulfill services. LifeCare’s systems do not store or transmit credit card information, however we partner with the trusted third party as specified in the “ [How We Share Your Information](https://wl.lifecare.com/group/guest/privacy-policy#_HOW_WE_SHARE) ” section.
* Public or Community Forums – In some cases, your Sponsor Organization may subscribe to a “classifieds” feature allowing you to post or purchase personal items for sale with other Members. In such cases, you would enter data types such as item description, pricing, pictures and contact information you wish to provide.
* Information Received from Third Parties – LifeCare may receive your Personal Information from third parties in connection with services. We categorize these sources as LifeCare Sourced and Affiliated Third parties.
* LifeCare Sourced – In order to provide you with the best web and communication experience, LifeCare utilizes several third parties to provide us information on how you use our website, how our website is performing, and the effectiveness of our email communication so we can continue to customize and improve your experience. This is in form of cookies placed on your computer. Please see the “Cookies” under the “ [How We Collect Information](https://wl.lifecare.com/group/guest/privacy-policy#_HOW_WE_COLLECT) ” section for more information.
* Affiliated Third Parties – LifeCare’s services maybe offered to you through a service you have with another service provider. As part of your agreement with them, you have agreed to provide information to LifeCare. In such cases, your name and email address will be collected by LifeCare.

**Anonymous Information** – means information that does not identify you personally, but can provide us with usage data, either individually or in the aggregate. Non-Identifiable Information may include demographic information, aggregated information, certain information collected automatically through your device such as web browser information, server log files, cookie technology, and other technologies, and other non-personally identifiable information collected by us or provided by you.

HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION
--------------------------

We may collect information from you in the following ways:

**By Request** : We may collect some information from you by asking that you provide it to us.

**Cookies** – We may use cookies on the LifeCare Sites to allow us to, among other things, measure activity and to personalize your experience. “Cookies” are small text files that reside on your computer to identify you as a unique user. For instance, cookies may enable us to remember your viewing preferences without requiring you to re-type a user-name and password. Cookies may also allow us to track your status or progress when requesting products, services, or information. Specifically, LifeCare leverages session cookies. These are not permanent cookies and are removed from when your browser closes or your computer is powered off. LifeCare also utilizes persistent cookies to enhance your experience with our site. If you choose, you can set your browser to reject cookies or you can manually delete individual or all of the cookies on your computer by following your browser’s help file directions. However, if your browser is set to reject cookies or you manually delete cookies, you may have some trouble accessing and using some of the pages and features that are currently on our website, or that we may put on our website in the future. To take full advantage of the www.lifecare.com experience, we recommend that you leave them turned on.

**Pixels** – A _tracking pixel_ is an HTML code snippet which is loaded when a user opens an email. It is useful for _tracking_ user behaviors to help us gage the effectiveness of our communications.

**Web Server Logs/IP Address** – The computers that deliver our web pages to you may record information. For example, a web server log may record the search terms you enter on our websites, the link you clicked to bring you to the web page, your IP address, or cookies that are set on your browser.

HOW WE USE PERSONAL INFORMATION
-------------------------------

We may use Personal Information for the following purposes:

* Verifying your identity so that we can be sure that all of our communications with you are secure and confidential, for application security, and to help prevent fraud and data loss.
* Responding to inquiries or requests from you.
* Delivering products and services to you.
* To send you marketing and promotional communications that we believe may be of interest to you.
* Customizing your experience on the website including managing and recording your preferences.
* Marketing, product development, and research purposes.
* Tracking resources and data accessed on the website.
* Developing reports regarding website usage, activity, and statistics.
* Assisting users experiencing website problems.
* Enabling certain functions and tools on this website.
* Tracking paths of visitors to this website and within this website.

If you decide that you do not want to receive commercial emails from us, you can “opt-out” from receiving such emails by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link provided at the bottom of every commercial email, unsubscribing within your website profile, or by emailing [**help@lifecare.com**](mailto:help@lifecare.com) .

If you decide at a later time that you would like to receive commercial emails from us, you can re-add yourself to our communication list.

HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION
------------------------

Unless required in connection with the provision of services, we will not share your Identifiable Personal Information with any third party except as set forth below:

Affiliates : We may share information with companies that we own or control, that are owned or controlled by us, or that are under common ownership or control.

Blogs, etc .: We may decide to allow users to share comments, testimonials, or other information. If you choose to submit such information to us, the information that you submit in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.

Law Enforcement : We may report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we reasonably believe to be unlawful, or that we reasonably believe may aid a law enforcement investigation into unlawful activity. In addition, we reserve the right to release your information to law enforcement agencies if we determine, in our sole judgment, that either you have violated our policies, or the release of your information may protect the rights, property, or safety of LifeCare, or another person.

Legal Process : We may share your information with others as required by, or permitted by, law. This may include sharing your information with governmental entities, or third parties in response to subpoenas, court orders, other legal process, or as we believe is necessary to exercise our legal rights, to defend against legal claims that have been brought against us, or to defend against possible legal claims that we determine in our sole discretion might be brought against us.

Referred Providers : We may share information with other companies or individuals that provide products or services that you have requested, that we think may be of interest to you or that provide us or you with services. In this case, we will only disclose the limited amount of information necessary to perform the services you have requested.

Subcontractors/Contractors/Vendors : We may share information with LifeCare subcontractors, contractors or vendors to enable them to perform certain services for us or you, including, but not limited to, provisions of services to you, and/or application maintenance and performance improvement tasks. In all such cases we will require the recipient to protect the information and use it only for the purpose it was provided.

Business Transactions : In the event that we, or any portion of our assets are sold or acquired, we may share all types of information with the acquiring company.

Sponsor Organizations : Generally identifiable information regarding your usage of services is not provided to your Sponsoring Organization. However, there are exceptions. In the event that a service requires imputing of income, payment of charges directly for your specific usage, or in the event that you mis-use the services in any way, information regarding your usage will be shared with your Sponsoring Organization.

Non-Identifiable Information is not Personal Information and may be shared, including being provided to your Sponsor Organization as part of de-identified aggregated reports.

HOW WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
----------------------------------------

We maintain reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the Personal Information that you provide. We comply with all applicable state and federal law pertaining to the security and confidentiality of Personal Information. Our secure server software encrypts information, ensuring that all Internet transactions from your PC to our servers remain private (unless sent by an unsecured means, such as e-mail). Use of this encryption is facilitated automatically. To protect the integrity and confidentiality of your Personal Information, our web servers reside behind firewalls. In addition to these security measures, only our Members who need access to your Personal Information to carry out their duties have access to that information. We accomplish this through both strong physical and logical access controls. Our Members must abide by our company’s privacy policy, and are subject to disciplinary action for any violation of that policy.

However, no security system is impenetrable and we cannot guarantee the security of our website, nor can we guarantee that the Personal Information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet, and we are not liable for the illegal acts of third parties such as criminal hackers. Further, while we are dedicated to securing our systems and services, you are responsible in protecting the privacy of your password(s) and account/profile registration information and ensuring that the Personal Data we maintain to identify you is kept up to date.

CHOICE AND CONSENT
------------------

While LifeCare maintains a secure site, you should know that computer use may be monitored by third parties such as network administrators, Sponsor Organizations, etc., and thus we cannot guarantee the security of information you disclose. You disclose such information at your own risk. By using the LifeCare Sites, you are consenting to the collection, use, disclosure and sharing of your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy.

PRIVACY OF CHILDREN
-------------------

LifeCare realizes that children under the age of 13 may not understand all the provisions of our policy or be able to make thoughtful decisions about the choices made available. We urge all parents to participate in their children’s exploration of the Internet and any online services, and to teach their children about protecting their Personal Information while online. Therefore, LifeCare will not knowingly allow users under the age of 13 to use the site without the consent of their parent or guardian.

THIRD PARTY CONTENT PROVIDERS/LINKS
-----------------------------------

You will find contents and products of other companies or organizations on our sites and/or links to the sites and services of our suppliers, licensors or other third parties. While we make efforts to monitor the sites or services, we do not control the contents or links that appear on these sites. We are not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by third parties, and information collected by third parties is not governed by LifeCare’s Privacy Policy. Each such third party is solely responsible for complying with the laws, rules and regulations applicable to its business, operation of its web site(s), and the use of your Personal Information, including all applicable laws, rules and regulations regarding the privacy and confidentiality of Personal Information. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies, or no policy (policies) at all. These sites or services, including their contents and links, may be constantly changing. By interacting with these sites, you are acknowledging their policies. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any third party sites or services before providing any of them with your Personal Information.

YOUR RIGHTS
-----------

You may have rights under certain state or federal laws applicable to your Personal Information. If you would like to request to review, correct, update, suppress or delete Personal Information that you have previously provided to us, you may contact us as set forth below. We will respond to your request consistent with our obligations under applicable law.

Please note, that generally we do not destroy Personal Information about you when your relationship with your Sponsoring Organization ends or your services terminate. It may be necessary retain or use certain information for the purpose described above even after your relationship ends or services terminate, or for recordkeeping purposes. There may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed. Regardless, all such information will continue to be treated and protected in accordance with the then current Privacy Policy.

CONTACTING LIFECARE ABOUT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

If you would like to make a request regarding your Personal Information, you can use the information below for your assistance:

* – Provides assistance in updating your information for usage of the website or issues related to the website;
* [dataprivacy@lifecare.com –](mailto:dataprivacy@lifecare.com%20-) Provides assistance with all other requests regarding your Personal Information

You may also:

**Call Us at:**

(800) 873-4636

**Write Us at:**

_LifeCare. Inc.  
(Attn: Security and Compliance Department)  
2 Armstrong Rd.  
Shelton, CT 06405_

CONCERNS
--------

Individuals may raise concerns regarding their Personal Information with LifeCare by submitting your concern as set forth below. Your submission must contain the following:

1. Your Name
2. Your Telephone Number
3. Your Email Address
4. Statement detailing your concern, including but not limited to:
    1. The identification of a real or potential harm that you have sustained or may sustain

Concerns may be made by email to [dataprivacy@lifecare.com](mailto:dataprivacy@lifecare.com) , by phone to VP – Security, Audit and Compliance at 203-291-3453, or in writing, addressed to:

_LifeCare. Inc.  
(Attn: Client Issues Department)  
2 Armstrong Rd.  
Shelton, CT 06405_

LifeCare will investigate all concerns raised regarding compliance with its Privacy Policy and/or applicable law. If a concern is found to be justified, we will take appropriate measures to immediately address areas of concern, to the extent determined necessary by LifeCare. An individual will be informed of the outcome of the investigation regarding his or her concern within a reasonable period of time.

**NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS**

LifeCare uses the data you provide to provision services you request or to improve our services offered to you. We do not sell your information for profit and value the confidentiality of your data. As our website links to other third party websites that allow you to optionally provide information to them, please see read the “Third Party Content Providers/Links” section of this policy. If you are a resident of California and would like to make a formal request for data inventory/export/removal, please contact us at [dataprivacy@lifecare.com](mailto:dataprivacy@lifecare.com) or use the contact information set forth in Privacy Policy. –

If you are a California resident, you may have certain additional rights. California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your Personal Information by LifeCare to third parties for direct marketing purposes. California Business and Professions Code Section 22581 permits registered users who are minors to request and obtain deletion of certain posted content. Visit the California Legislative Website for more information in regards to your rights under the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018.

**CHANGES**

We may change the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time. This Privacy Policy will be deemedto be automatically changed as necessary to comply withchanges required by applicable law. Any changes will beeffective for all of the information that we already haveabout you, as well as any information that we may receive inthe future.

ACCEPTANCE OF TERMS
-------------------

By using any of the LifeCare Sites, you signify your acceptance of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our sites. Your continued use of the LifeCare Sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean that you accept those changes.

Last Updated: December 31, 2019

Copyright © 2024 Lifecare, Inc. All rights reserved | [Terms & Conditions](https://www.lifecare.com/terms-conditions) | [Privacy Policy](https://www.lifecare.com/privacy-policy)
